

ABOUT ME

I'm a game programmer specializing in object-oriented programming, with 3 years of experience in the industry, including the development of two commercially published games.

I worked at Melbot, where I was involved in the development of commercial games for consoles and handled their ports

Additionally, I gained experience working for Magnetic, where I focused on mobile game development for a live game with over +500k downloads.

For both companies, I have developed tools which have been used in production.

I'm a proactive and sociable person, always excited to take on new challenges and experiences.

CONTACT

- +34 636-98-24-40
- marina.chava24@gmail.com
- Portfolio Personal web
- LinkedIn

LANGUAGES

- Spanish (Native)
- Catalan (Native)
- English (Advanced)

MARINA CHAVARRIA

GAME PROGRAMMER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Console Game Programmer - Melbot

January 2022-April 2023 October 2023 - Current

Nick Jr Party Adventure - PC & Console - Unity

- Implement key gameplay systems. (level, menus, rewards...)
- Re-develop a new UI system with DoTween, for improved performance.
- Develop the PlayStation 5 port and supported the PlayStation 4 port.
- Optimizing the game for Switch due to its limitations.
- Developed a tool for creating levels that was highly flexible, allowing designers and artists to seamlessly incorporate their artwork into the tool, with the map adapting to the art.
- Working with the Nintendo SDK, PS5 and PS4.
- Develop the marketing build (shortcuts, cheats, special cameras...)

My Little Pony A Maretime Bay Adventure - PC & Console - Unity

- · Develop gameplay features.
- Responsible for the Play Station 5 port.
- Enhance its performance and resolve existing bugs.
- Working with the Nintendo SDK and Xbox to assist in the development.

Mobile Game Programmer - Magnetic

April 2023 - October 2023

Art Heist Puzzle - Android and IOS - Unity

- Developed key features for a live game with over 500k downloads.
- Implementation of code for the client-server communication.
- · Actively applied dependency injection in the codebase.
- Integrated third-party libraries and SDK into existing project.
- Debugged complex problems in existing code base.
- Develop the first in-game purchase system, from the client side.
- · Participated in design meetings with other team members to discuss ideas for future content.

Unity teacher - Xnergic Tecnocampus

October 2020 - January 2022

· Provide classes about Unity, Scratch, and Arduino to children throughout the year.

EDUCATION

Videogame Programming and Design

2018 - 2023

Tecnocampus Pompeu Fabra

COMPETENCES

- C#
- C++
- Lua

Engines

- Unity
- Unreal
- Defold

Communication

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork
- Attention to detail
- · Time managment

Languages

- Python